# **Cameron Hope**

<u>cameron@cameronhope.co.uk</u> • (+44) 07934 331817 • Winchester, Hampshire www.cameronhope.co.uk/portfolio

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Highly motivated Computer Science graduate with a first-class honours degree. Experienced in software development and AI training with skills in Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Python, C#, HTML, and CSS. Determined, self-starter with an aptitude for problem solving and a passion for technology.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### Al Code Reviewer | Data Annotation

November 2024 - Present

- Contributing to the development of AI models through precise data reviewing, ensuring accuracy and relevance
- Utilising technical expertise to ensure high-quality training data for machine learning applications
- Applying critical thinking and attention to detail in evaluating code and descriptions in AI-generated responses
- Providing constructive feedback to enhance the performance and reliability of AI systems

## IT Work / Gap Year

December 2022 - November 2024

- Travelled across Asia and Europe visiting 12 countries including Malaysia, Thailand, Vietnam, and Switzerland
- Worked nightshifts as a warehouse operative at the Southampton Royal Mail Centre
- Developed bespoke websites and apps, including <u>www.eleanorwakefield.com</u>, and a personal portfolio website
- Assisted various local clients with home computing needs

IBM July 2017

Work Experience Hursley, Hampshire

- Worked in a team to create test cases for bulk data processing on an IBM mainframe
- Gained foundational understanding of Java concepts and technical troubleshooting

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Reading** 

**September 2020 - July 2023** 

**BSc (Hons) Computer Science (1st)** 

Reading, Berkshire

## **Individual Project:**

- Developed a multiplayer networked game using C# and Unity
- Designed and implemented gameplay mechanics and network functionality

### **Peter Symonds College**

**September 2018 - July 2020** 

3 A Levels: Computer Science, Mathematics, and Physics

### Kings' School Winchester

September 2013 - July 2018

10 GCSES including Mathematics, English, Computer Science, and Combined Science

## **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, Typescript, C#, Python, HTML, CSS
- Frameworks & Libraries: Tailwind CSS, React, Next.js, Node.js, Three.js, Shadon
- Databases: MongoDB, Firebase
- Tools & Platforms: Windows, Linux, Visual Studio Code, Git, Vercel, Cloudflare, Unity
- Interests: Travel, live music, bodybuilding, gaming, building computers, coding, Star Wars, superheroes

#### **OTHER**

- Full UK Driving License (Car Owner)
- DBS Checked
- Portfolio: www.cameronhope.co.uk/portfolio
- Github: www.github.com/chope12